A Guide to the Trio Beauty Salon Records, 1935-2007: SC 0207
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
Trio Beauty Salon Records,
1935-2007
Special Collections, James Madison University
Clatterbuck, Beulah Ruth Kerns, 1915-2017
SC 0207
1.39 cubic feet; 3 boxes
The Trio Beauty Salon Records, 1935-2007, consist of three boxes containing various records related to the Trio Beauty Salon in Harrisonburg, Virginia including legal and financial documents, record books, and personal documents of the operators of the salon.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection. Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the James Madison University Special Collections Library to use this collection.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Beulah Ruth Kearns Clatterbuck on April 13, 2012.
Bio/Historical Note
Trio Beauty Salon opened on July 15, 1941 at 14 Newman Ave, Harrisonburg, Virginia. It was known formerly as the Gay Lynn Beauty Shop. The three partners of the Trio Beauty Salon were Flora Evelyn Taylor Lamb, Mildred Bridges, and Ava Gowl, but also included Ruby Dove and Beulah Ruth Kerns Clatterbuck as owners and operators. The salon was open for 35 years before closing in 1976. After closing the salon, the owners continued to work elsewhere in the Harrisonburg area, and kept records of where they went.
Scope and Content
The Trio Beauty Salon Records consist of various documents and records pertaining to the Trio Beauty Salon and its owners and operators, including business, financial, and personal documents. The collection comprises business records, leases and agreements, tax and financial documents, and personal records of Beulah Ruth Kerns Clatterbuck.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into the following series and subseries:
Series 1: Legal Files, 1937-1977
Series 2: Financial Records, 1937-1976
Subseries 2.1: Tax Returns and Statements, 1937-1976
Subseries 2.2: Record Books, 1938-1976
Series 3: Personal Records, 1935-2007
All series and subseries are arranged chronologically.
Location of Originals
Original documents relating to Beulah Ruth Kerns Clatterbuck were retained by the owner. Original documents were photocopied for this collection.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Trio Beauty Salon -- Records and correspondence; Trio Beauty Salon -- History; Beauty shops -- Virginia -- Harrisonburg; Beauty operators -- Virginia -- Harrisonburg; Women-owned business enterprises -- Virginia -- Harrisonburg; Beauty shops -- Virginia -- Rockingham County; Beauty operators -- Virginia -- Rockingham County; Women-owned business enterprises -- Virginia -- Rockingham County; Harrisonburg (Va.) -- Economic conditions; Rockingham County (Va.) -- Economic conditions; Harrisonburg (Va.) -- History -- Sources; Rockingham County (Va.) -- History -- Sources; Virginia -- History, Local -- Sources
- Series 1: Legal Files, 1937-1977
  Scope and Content
  This series contains legal documents and correspondence for Trio Beauty Salon from the years 1937-1977, including business and financial records, letters from the U.S. Department of Labor, and one photograph of the owners and operators.
  - Partnership Agreements, 1937-1943 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Property Leases, 1937-1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Change of Business Name Document, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Photograph (photocopy), 1941 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Helen Curtis Cold Wave Franchise, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1946-1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bank Account Records, 1955-1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Withholding Exemption Certificates, 1962-1966 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Virginia Hairdressing Regulations, 1963-1975 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Advertising for Other Companies, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Insurance, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Application for Directory Advertising, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Blueprint, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Series 2: Financial Records, 1937-1976
  Arranged into two subseries: Tax Returns and Statements, 1937-1976 and Record Books, 1938-1976. Arranged chronologically within each series.
  - Subseries 2.1: Tax Returns and Statements, 1937-1976
    Contains both state and federal tax returns, Harrisonburg taxes, and tax related documents and financial statements. Folders labeled Tax Returns consists of only returns and folders labeled Tax Documents consists of returns and other tax related records.
    - Federal Tax Return, 1937-1939 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Financial Statements, 1937-1953 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Virginia Tax Return, 1937-1939 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Federal Tax Return, 1940-1949 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Virginia Tax Return, 1940-1949 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Harrisonburg Taxes, 1944-1976 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Federal Tax Return, 1951-1959 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Virginia Tax Documents, 1951-1959 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Federal Tax Return, 1960-1969 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Virginia Tax Documents, 1960-1969 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Federal Tax Documents, 1970-1976 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Virginia Tax Documents, 1970-1976 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 2.2: Record Books, 1938-1976
    contains financial records documenting costs and expenses of operation of Trio Beauty Salon, including monthly expenses in terms of supplies, wages, taxes, rent, lighting, repairs, equipment and miscellaneous expenses. Record books are housed in Oversize Hollinger boxes.
    - Book 1, January 1938-December 1943 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Book 2, January 1944-December 1949 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Book 3, January 1950-December 1954 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Book 4, August 1954-December 1958 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Book 5, January 1959-December 1962 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Book 6, January 1963-December 1966 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Book 7, January 1967-December 1971 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Book 8, January 1972-December 1976 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Series 3: Personal Records, 1935-2007
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains personal documents of Beulah Ruth Kerns Clatterbuck, including items related to the practice of cosmetology and a brief autobiography of her life.
  - Beauty School Notes of Beulah Ruth Kerns, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Certificate to Use Frederics Method, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Diploma from Paulinas Beauty School, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - High School Diploma of Beulah Ruth Kerns, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Certificate of Authorization to be a Practicing Hairdresser, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Cosmetology Licenses for Beulah Ruth Kerns Clatterbuck, 1963-2004 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Virginia Board of Cosmetology Rules, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Obituary for Flora Evelyn Lamb, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Brief Autobiography of Beulah Ruth Kerns, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)